Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/tuantottii (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Knowledge Graph-Based Natural Language Processing

LangChain

Neo4j

Honors-Awards

Top 15 VNU Innovation Start-up

Top 4, Medical and Pharmaceutical Innovations 2022

Top 4 Neuron

B-type scholarship

B-type scholarship

Publications

Enhancing Multi-label Vulnerability Detection of Smart Contract using Language Mode

Tuan Nguyen

Al Engineer

Hanoi Capital Region

Summary

As an experienced Natural Language Processing (NLP) Engineer and Researcher, I have developed expertise in the development of NLP solutions for my corporation. My key skills include researching, optimizing NLP models, and writing journal articles. I have successfully developed and implemented NLP solutions for various tasks such as information retrieval, text classification, and question-answering. I am motivated to learn and grow every day. Open to feedback, Team player with good communication and soft skills. I got experience working under pressure and meeting deadlines.

Experience

Toshiba Software Development (Vietnam)
Al Engineer
July 2024 - Present (11 months)
Hanoi Capital Region

- Developed and deployed a chatbot application utilizing Large Language Models (such as GPT) and GraphRAG to enhance the chatbot's accuracy and faithfulness.
- Created a Knowledge Graph Construction pipeline that unified diverse maintenance datasets, improving decision-making precision.

FTECH CO., LTD

Artificial Intelligence Engineer August 2023 - January 2024 (6 months)

Developed and implemented an NLP-based system to search the duplicate Vietnamese content used for other services like question-answering, and question generation.

Research and evaluate new NLP technologies and techniques for enhancing the sentence embedding task such as prompt-based method, contrastive learning, and so on.

Bach Khoa Cyber Security
Artificial Intelligence Researcher

January 2023 - December 2023 (1 year)

Developed and implemented a neural network-based natural language processing (NLP) model to detect and classify smart contract vulnerabilities as well as to enhance the performance of the model.

Trained and leveraged the traditional feature extraction algorithms as well as state-of-the-art models such as SecBERT for downstream tasks to propose a model in the academic paper.

Cooperated with Associate Professor, Ph.D., and other students to write journal articles.

NCCPLUS VIETNAM

Software Engineer April 2022 - December 2022 (9 months) Vietnam

Built RESTful API for a check-in service that served JavaScript front-end using Java Spring framework.

Collaborated with team members in the development of software to develop the new functionalities.

Education

Hanoi University of Science and Technology
Engineer's degree, Information Technology · (September 2019 - July 2024)